CURRICULUM VITAE

SHIBA PRASAD MISHRA

Contact No - 9699658588(M)

Email: sibabimit@gmail.com

Plot No.-330/3680, C/o – Rekharani Dash Mahatab Road, Opp Mula Padia, Lingaraj Nagar, Lane 1, Old Town, Bhubaneshwar – 751002 Odisha.

Career Objectives:-

Seek to work in an environment that will challenge me further; while allowing me to contribute to the continued growth and success of the organization. Obtain a position that will provide me the ability to apply my skills and work experience to a growing industry. Look forward to working with a company that promotes quality products and services; and provides me with the opportunity to meet and exceed assigned goals.

MBA in Finance having more than 8 years of experience in security & Manpower industry as a Deputy Manager - Taxation (Finance and Accounts) and ascertaining Indirect Tax Liabilities as well as helping the statutory and Tax auditors in completion of audit and conclusion reports and reporting directly to DGM and higher management like CFO, Director-Finance.

Key Skills:

Good knowledge in GST and Service Tax.

Good Team Player & Enjoy sharing knowledge and encouraging colleagues to achieve their specific goals.

Problem solving - Resolving queries in a methodical manner independently as well as with team members to find appropriate and efficient solutions.

Communication – Effective communicator to manage and solve internal and external queries via actively listening and probing questions

Computer Skill:

Good in Tally along with JD Edwards Accounting.

Certification in Financial Accounting-Tally 9.0 (Computerised Accounting Software)

Academic Qualifications:-

Qualification	Name of the Institution	Year
MBA Finance	Bhubaneswar Institute of Management and Information Technology under BPUT with a CGPA 7.18	2009
Bachelor of Commerce	S.C.S (A) College, Utkal University, Orissa	2003
H.S.C. (12 th Std.)	S.C.S. (L) College, CHSE, Orissa	2000
S.S.C. (10 th Std.)	Bhargabi High School, BSE Orissa	1998

Work Experience:

Working as Dy. Corporate Manager – Accounts & Taxation at M/s. Tops
 Security Limited from April 2012 to till date.

Job Profile:

- Filing of monthly GST returns and half-yearly Service Tax Returns, making online payment of GST and Service Tax of all the registrations across India and all types of accounting entries related to GST and Service Tax in books of accounts.
- Online Migration from VAT to GST and Service Tax to GST.
- Instruction to branch accountants on classification, valuation, applicability of GST and Service tax on transactions and admissibility to tax benefits/exemptions. Verification and rectification of entries.
- Undertaking comprehensive reviews of GST and Service Tax to identify the actual as well as compliance gaps.
- Conducting detailed indirect tax due diligence reviews (Inward & Outward). Meeting the requirements of Auditor for Statutory Audit and Tax Audit.
- Meeting Service Tax officers on monthly basis and providing details of Service Tax.
- Reply to SCNs issued by Service Tax authorities for all the respective branches with the help of Legal Advisers.
- Keeping and verifying the records of branch wise GST and ST liabilities with the help of Oracle based accounting software.
- Filing of appeal and drafting replies with the help of Legal Advisors in response to the letters and orders issued by Service Tax Department.

2. Worked as an Accounts Assistant at M/s. Toshali Tours & Travels from August 2010 to April 2012.

Job Profile:

- Maintaining accounts with Tally 9.0 ERP including Reconciliation of Bank accounts on daily basis.
- Keeping proper accounting records of each and everything, preparing payments to vendors for transport bookings and room bookings, following up for payments from Customers, etc.
- Reporting monthly data to Head Office.
- Meeting the requirements of Auditor for Statutory Audit.
- 3. Worked as an Accounts Executive at M/s. RT Outsourcing Services Limited from August 2009 to July 2010.

Job Profile:

- Arranging funds for travelling and conveyance allowance of all employees of the branch by making entries in the Software.
- Verification of vouchers, reconciliation of employee ledger on daily basis.
- Credit monitoring & follow up for invoices from vendors.
- Monthly reconciling the bank accounts and vendor ledgers.
- Preparation of MIS on weekly and monthly basis and reports to Head Office.

4. Worked as an Accounts Executive at M/s. Sneba Pharmaceuticals from July 2004 to July 2007.

Job Profile:

- Credit monitoring & follow up for invoices from vendors.
- Maintaining of accounts both manually and computerized.
- Keeping all the records of every vendors or customers individually.
- Purchase orders processing for payments and follow-up of payments from customers.
- Making payments in cheques to vendors against goods received by our organization.

Summer Project:-

Undergone two-month summer internship training program at Punjab National Bank, Circle Office, Bhubaneshwar in the Credit Appraisal System of Punjab National Bank.

Dissertation:-

A dissertation report on the "Impact on the stock market volatility due to the introduction of Derivatives".

Personal Details:-

Father's Name : Mr. S.N. Mishra Mother's Name : Mrs. S. Mishra.

Permanent Address: C/o:- Mr. Satyanarayan Mishra.

At/Po: - Biranarasinghpur Via/PS:- Chandanpur

Dist:- Puri, Pin-752012, State:- Orissa

Date of Birth : 15th July 1983

Gender : Male
Marital Status : Married
Religion : Hindu
Nationality : Indian

Languages known : Oriya, English & Hindi.

Hobbies : Playing cricket and football, meeting new people.

I do hereby declare that the information furnished above is true to the best of my knowledge and belief.